Joseph Hirotsu

New York, NY (open to relocation) | 310-780-2539 | jhirotsu@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack software engineer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming, coming from 10+ years of experience as an executive chef. Throughout my time at Flatiron School, I demonstrated the ability to develop and integrate solutions through individual and team projects with very short deadlines. I often took the lead in team settings to plan wireframes and responsibilities, design components, and map actionable steps to deliver successful results. Continuing growth through studying JavaScript, ReactJS, CSS, Data Structures and Algorithms, Python, TypeScript, Web3 and current Industry events.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies/Skills: Ruby on Rails, TypeScript, ReactJS, JavaScript, React Native, Swift, Redux, Context API, Thunk, PostgreSQL, RESTFUL Routing, SQL, JSON, A/B testing, HTML, Tailwind, CSS, Figma

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Primetime - Fullstack Food Delivery App - GitHub Front-end || GitHub Back-end

A web app created for ordering food at live sporting events, designed with accessibility in mind. Users include the elderly with limited mobility, those with disabilities, parents with children, and spectators who do not want to miss the action.

- Languages/Frameworks: React Native, Ruby on Rails, Redux, Expo, CSS.
- For my capstone project I decided to learn React Native and Redux. I had designed frameworks on Figma and I was determined to learn Native to make a functional mobile app.

Olio, The Olive Oil Store - Fullstack E-Commerce - GitHub || GitHub Front-end || GitHub-Back-end

A TypeScript E-commerce App for an olive oil specialty store designed with Tailwind.

- Languages/Frameworks: Typescript, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Tailwind CSS
- Features: Responsive design, Context API, Shopping Cart, Stripe Payment, Admin portal.

LinkedIn UI - React and Styled-Components - GitHub

This project is a UI replica of the LinkedIn landing page and homepage. The UI has a lot of components I had fun building from scratch.

- Languages/Frameworks: Javascript, ReactJS, Styled-Components/CSS.
- Features: Slider, Drop-down menu, Flex-box

EXPERIENCE

My time in bootcamp parallels my skills as an executive chef with 10 years experience where I managed 'full-stack' operations and balanced front-of-the-house and back-of-the-house teams for success. Among the many skills required as a hospitality executive manager, I managed and trained teams, created dishes that impressed shareholders and customers with varying demands, and operated full-scale, multi-million dollar revenue businesses.

Chef (Executive chef, Chef de cuisine, Entrepreneur), please see LinkedIn for detailed timeline

New York, NY 2012-2022

Highlights: Howard Hughes (Executive chef, 2019-2020), Del Posto (2013-15), Roosterboy (Owner/Chef, 2016-2022)

- 10+ years in the food industry achieving executive chef and business owner roles.
- At Howard Hughes, I managed restaurant properties with \$4M+ sales. Duties include Profit & Loss meetings with the corporate team, payroll & scheduling, daily ordering & receiving, costing & inventory, managing a team of 40+ personnel. Ensuring that we were all working together to meet our common goal, day after day, with the end goal to serve our customers to have the best experience possible.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and React

New York, NY
2022

UCLA Los Angeles, CA